josephjoseph.com 2019-09-10

# Privacy Policy

We at Joseph Joseph Ltd take the privacy of all our visitors very seriously, and therefore have set out this policy to state our position regarding your data privacy and the use of cookies (snippets of data captured by your browsing on our website).

##### Overview

This policy covers all the data that is shared with us on www.josephjoseph.com and explanations on what happens to any personal data you provide to us, or that is obtained via this website or by email sent to us directly.

The policy covers any means to access the website, whether through a phone, computer or tablet and will provide information about:

  * How we use your data;
  * What personal data we collect;
  * How we ensure your privacy is maintained; and
  * Your legal rights relating to your personal data.

##### Your information as personal data

We view personal data as the following:

Name, identification numbers, location data and online identifier(s); these relating to both automated and manually filed data, electronic and physical. There are many more data categories but we list these as they are the only ones currently captured by us,that pertain to you.

##### How we use your information

We use various pieces of your personal information in different ways, sometimes with two or more functions, see the below tables for our explanations on why we process that data.

**-    ** **Name & contact details**

  * To deliver your order and perform our contract with you.
  * To send you order updates by text or email and perform our contract with you.
  * For fraud prevention and detection. To prevent and detect fraud against you or Joseph Joseph.
  * Send you information about our products and services by email, text or post. To keep you up to date. We only send this with your permission.
  * Show you Joseph Joseph adverts as you browse the web. To keep you up to date with our latest products and offers.
  * Find out more about what you and other customers like. To offer personalised and relevant experience

-    **Date of birth**

  * Send you a birthday offer by email, text or post. To wish you a happy birthday and include an offer from us
  * Fraud prevention and detection. To prevent and detect fraud against you or Joseph Joseph.

**-    Payment**

  * Take payment and give refund. To perform our contract with you.
  * Fraud prevention and detection. To prevent and detect fraud against you or Joseph Joseph.

**-    Purchase history & whishlist items**

  * Sell Joseph Joseph products online. To perform our contract with you.
  * Find out more about what you and other customers like. To offer personalised and relevant experience
  * Fraud prevention and detection. To prevent and detect fraud against you or Joseph Joseph.
  * For customer service and to manage returns. To perform our contract with you.

**-    Your contact history with us**

  * For customer service. To perform our contract with you
  * Train our customer care team. To deliver the best possible customer experience.

**-    Your device type, IP address, location data and how you browse our website**

  * Set default options for you (language, currency, delivery country etc.). To deliver a convenient shopping experience.
  * Improve our website and make it easier for you to shop and browse.
  * Fraud prevention and detection. To prevent and detect fraud against you or Joseph Joseph.

**-    Your response to surveys, competitions and promotions**

  * To Run surveys, competitions and promotions and perform our contract with you.

You do not have to provide any personal information to us, and we will cover how you can opt in and out of certain specifics that may not be absolutely necessary to provide a service to you.

In some cases where you do not provide us with data you may not be able to order from the site and would be unlikely to receive our optimal customer experience.

##### Guest users

We view a Guest User as someone who selects “Checkout as a guest” via checkout on the website and thus we would not identify you to the same extent as a Registered User with an active Joseph Joseph account.

All the data provided by a Guest User in the context of an order will be anonymised once the order is fulfilled. Please bear in mind that we will keep the value of that order and keep only non-identifying location data such as County/State/Province and Country only.

##### Our internal systems tests

Our Registered Users’ data provided in the context of an order will not only be used in fulfilling your order but also to carry out internal systems tests, including IT procedures, and research and data analysis to improve the Joseph Joseph website and app. To do so, the orders and data will be mirrored in a closed off test system.

##### Sharing data with third parties

We  **do not sell, and will not sell,**  any of your personal data to Third Parties. However, to be able to make some of our services available to you, we share your data with the following companies:

-   Order related companies, such as:

  * Payment service providers, warehouses, order packers and delivery companies

-   Professional service providers and analytics, such as;

  * Marketing agencies, advertising partners and website hosts

-   Law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies

##### Marketing & advertising - opt in/opt out

**MARKETING**

We will only send you marketing messages with your permission. If you wish to receive marketing messages from us, we will keep you updated by email, text or post.

It is important to note that Marketing messages do not include service messages or customer care communications. An example of each being:

  * Order/despatch confirmations via email/text
  * Intelligent Waste Registration

 However, if you do not wish to receive any further email messages from us, you can:

  *  Go to your  ** _account_**  >  ** _my_**   ** _newsletter_**  or  ** _newsletter_**   ** _subscription_** , untick the  ** _General_**   ** _subscription_**  box and  ** _save_**  your choice

**Or**

  * Click on the  **unsubscribe**  link in any email marketing

**Or**

  * Contact our  **Customer Care team**.

If you do not wish to receive any further posted mailings from us, you can contact our  **Customer Care team** , include your full name and address

**ONLINE ADVERTISING**

We engage in online advertising to keep you aware of what we are up to and to help you see and find our products more easily, based on you.

We target our Joseph Joseph banners and ads to you when you are on  **other**  websites and apps, done through a variety of means and exercises, such as:

  * Web beacons
  * Pixels
  * Ad Tags
  * Cookies
  * Mobile Identifiers
  * Specific services offered by some sites and social networks, such as: Facebook’s Custom Audience service and Google Adwords User Lists.

The banners and ads you see are based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of our website through means such as but not limited to; Joseph Joseph Search History, not to be confused with your own browser search history, and our banners or ads you have previously clicked on.

**HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOU DATA?**

We will keep the following types of data for the stated lengths:

-   Financial Data:

  * Standard, 7 Years
  * Where Fraud and/or Enforcement is involved, up to 20 years

-   Online Account:

  * As long as the account is active

**Or**

  * As long as additional service(s) is agreed such as Intelligent Waste 10-year guarantee

-   Legal/Law Enforcement:

  * As long as ordered, in a bid to; resolve disputes, prevent fraud/abuse, enforce terms and conditions

##### Your rights

According to GDPR you have all your rights to do any of the following to your personal information:

  * Rights to be informed: about how we are handling your personal data and where it is going.
  * Rights to rectify: correct inaccuracies of data extending to incomplete data rectification.
  * Rights to be forgotten: destroy physical data, delete electronic data; extending to that of where data is passed to a third party we are directly liable.
  * Rights to restrict/withdraw consent: when you would like to contest your data’s accuracy; if we process your data unlawfully but you do not want to be fully forgotten; if we no longer need your data but you would like to begin or defend a legal claim(s); if agreements are being made in terms of the other rights.
  * Rights to Data Portability: when you would like a copy of all the data we hold about you, agreements of how it will be provided settled on request.
  * Rights to Object: when you have reason to stop us processing your data based on our processes, such as cancelling the sending of marketing materials.
  * Rights to Object to Supervisory Authority: when you would like to take a case to a data protection regulator
  * Rights to Appropriate Decision Making: when Joseph Joseph is not making decisions on your behalf based purely on automated procedures and to give you the power to actively have choice over the processing.

 If you want to exercise your rights, have a complaint, or just have questions, please contact our Customer Care team.

##### How can you help protect your data

**Card details**

Joseph Joseph  **will never**  ask you to confirm any bank account or credit card details via email or any other means such as Direct Messaging/Instant Messaging extending to that of Social Media Sites, over the phone or Web/Phone applications extending to that of instances like Whatsapp and Facebook Messenger.

 If you receive an email claiming to be from Joseph Joseph asking you to do so, please do not respond then get in touch with our Customer Care team, as this will help us to protect everyone in the future.

**Public computer or device**

If you are using a computer/phone device in a public location and/or on a public Wi-Fi, we recommend that you always log out and close the website browser when you complete an online session.

**Security measures**

In addition, we recommend that you take the following security measures to enhance your online safety both in relation to Joseph Joseph and more generally:

Keep your account passwords private. Remember, anyone who knows your password has an increased chance to be able to access your account.

When creating a password:

  * Use at least 8 characters; A combination of letters, numbers and symbols too, this will increase strength and decrease an attacker’s ability to crack.
  * Do not use dictionary words, your name, email address, or other personal data that can be easily obtained and/or guessed.
  * We also recommend that you frequently change your password, you can do this accessing your account, clicking  ** _my details_**  >  ** _change password  _**>  ** _enter current_**  and  ** _new password_**  and remember to click on  ** _save_**.

Avoid using the same password for multiple online accounts.

##### Privacy changes

We may change this page from time to time to reflect how we are processing your data, if we make significant changes we will make it clear on the Joseph Joseph website and any of our other services, or by some other means of contact to the best of our ability.

##### Cookie policy

Our website uses cookies to collect information relating to; browsing and purchasing behaviour by people who access our websites, information about pages viewed, products purchased and the customer journey around our websites.

 For more information, please refer to our [ **Cookie Policy**](http://josephjoseph.com/cookies-policy "Cookie Policy").

##### Contact us

If you have any questions or feedback about this policy, would like us to stop using your information, want to exercise any of your rights as set out above, or have a criticism, please do not hesitate to contact our  **Customer Care**  team, who will be happy to answer any questions you may have and are trained at dealing with any personal data matters.

 If you would prefer to write to us then our contact address is:

Joseph Joseph,

100 Union Street,

London,

SE1 0NL,

United Kingdom

As we understand it is important to recognise physical information counts in our policy, we will shred any documents that contain personal data as well as providing the same rights to physical information as electronic.

Last update: 09/05/2019
